A Guide to the Papers of Edward E. Younger, 1937-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- II. Personal Papers
  - Papers re India
    - U.S. Educational Foundation in India 1957-1958; 1963-1967, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - American Express 1957-1958 (Box 18)
    - Newsclippings and Printed Material 1957-1960 (Box 18)
    - Indian Greeting Cards n.d. (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous 1957-1960 (Box 19)
  - Papers re Naval War College
    - Lecture: "The Possessory Rights of the Hudson's Bay Company...1846-1871" ca. 1960, TMs (Box 19)
    - Lecture: "The Current Situation" 1960, TMs (Box 19)
    - Lecture: "The Dynamics of Neutralism" 1960, TMs, AMs (Box 19)
    - Lecture: "The Significance and Influence of India" 1960, TMs (Box 19)
    - Lecture: "The Background of Global Strategic Commitments of the United States" 1961, TMs (Box 19)
    - Correspondence 1958-1966, n.d., 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Certificates, Commendation, Personnel Forms 1960-1961 (Box 19)
    - Memoranda, Schedules, Reports 1960-1961 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous 1960-1961 (Box 19)
  - Professional Organizations
    - Albemarle County Historical Society 1951-1958 (Box 20)
    - Albemarle County Historical Society: Board of Directors and Executive Committee 1974-1975 (Box 20)
    - Albemarle County Historical Society: Acknowledgements of Gifts 1974-1975 (Box 20)
    - Albemarle County Historical Society: General Correspondence 1974-1979, n.d. (Box 20)
    - Albemarle County Historical Society: Minutes of Meetings 1974-1976 (Box 20)
    - Albemarle County Historical Society: Reports of Treasurer and of Committees 1974-1975 (Box 20)
    - Albemarle County Historical Society: Magazine of ...County History, Programs 1974-1975 (Box 20)
    - Albemarle County Historical Society: Material re Moore's History of Albemarle County 1974-1975 (Box 20)
    - Albemarle County Society: Material from the University Historian 1974-1975 (Box 20)
    - Albemarle County Historical Society: Daily Work File 1975-1976 (Box 20)
    - Albemarle County Historical Society: Genealogy 1974-1976 (Box 20)
    - American Historical Association: "Gilded Age Dissent" 1955-1956 (Box 20)
    - American Historical Association: "Historians and the Federal Government" 1955-1958, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - American Historical Association 1962-1965 (Box 20)
    - Civil War Centennial Committee 1959-1961 (Box 21)
    - Mississippi Valley Historical Association 1949-1962, n.d., 3 folders (Box 21)
    - National Historical Publications Commission 1964-1965 (Box 21)
    - Phi Beta Kappa 1963-1975 (Box 21)
    - Society for Historians of American Foreign Relations 1976-1977 (Box 21)
    - Southern Historical Association 1951-1960 May, 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Southern Historical Association 1960 June-Dec., 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Southern Historical Association Programs 1960 (Box 22)
    - Southern Historical Association: Summaries of 1960 Meeting 1960-1961 (Box 22)
    - Southern Historical Association: Final Report on 1960 Meeting 1960 (Box 22)
    - Southern Historical Association 1961-1964, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Southern Historical Association 1965-1973, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Virginia Historical Society 1969-1974 (Box 23)
    - Virginia History Federation 1967-1969 (Box 23)
    - Virginia Social Science Association 1952-1973, n.d., 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Virginia Social Science Association: Presidency 1971-1972, n.d., 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous Professional Activities 1946-1979, 2 folders (Box 23)
- III. General Correspondence
  - Correspondence 1944-1955 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence 1956 Jan. - 1959 July (Box 25)
  - Correspondence 1959 Aug. - 1963 April (Box 26)
  - Correspondence 1963 May-1965 March (Box 27)
  - Correspondence 1965 Apr. - 1979, n.d. (Box 28)
- IV. History Department Papers
  - Correspondence 1951-1956 Jan. (Box 29)
  - Correspondence 1956 May-1963, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Abernethy, Thomas Perkins, Memorial Resolution 1975-1976 (Box 30)
  - Alumni Correspondence 1962-1965 Dec., 3 folders (Box 30)
  - American Studies 1962, n.d. (Box 30)
  - American Studies Abroad 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Annual Reports 1958-1975 (Box 30)
  - Budget 1955-1965 (Box 30)
  - Chairman, Search Committee 1971-1973 (Box 30)
  - Courses-Book Orders 1965 (Box 31)
  - Courses-Book Orders, Library 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 1-2 1963-1965 (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 7, Reading Lists and Exams 1948-1962 (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 8, Reading Lists and Exams 1949-1951, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 7-8, Miscellaneous 1962-1965 (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 103-104 1947-1959, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 105 1946-1959 (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 106 1947-1959 (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 145-146 1958-1965, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 145-146, Exams 1954-1962 (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 207-208 1963-1967, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 237-238 1962-1972 (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 305-306 1961-1966, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 487 1976-1978, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 515 1971-1975, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Courses-History 835-836 1972-1976, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Courses-Project Social Studies 1962-1963 (Box 32)
  - Courses-Registration 1959-1965 (Box 32)
  - Courses-Teacher Preparation in American History and Civilization 1962-1965 (Box 32)
  - Duquesne History Forum 1973-1974 (Box 32)
  - Faculty Parties 1962-1963 (Box 32)
  - Faculty Recruiting 1962-1963, & 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Faculty Promotions 1971-1972 (Box 32)
  - Faculty Recruiting, East European and Russian History 1964-1965 (Box 32)
  - Faculty Recruiting, Far Eastern History 1959-1963 (Box 32)
  - Faculty Recruiting, U.S. History 1961-1962 (Box 32)
  - Fellowships-Experienced Teacher Fellowship Program 1965-1967 (Box 32)
  - Fellowships-Ford Fellowship for Black Students 1968-1969 (Box 32)
  - Fellowships-National Defense Education Act 1960-1965, n.d., 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Fellowships-Stettinius 1961-1970, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Fellowships-Woodrow Wilson 1964-1966, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Fellowships-Miscellaneous 1963-1965, 1968, n.d., 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Ford Foundation Proposal and Social Science Research 1958 (Box 33)
  - Foreign Language Exam 1962-1964 (Box 33)
  - Foundations and Grants 1949-1952 (Box 33)
  - Graduate Committee 1962-1964, 1965, n.d., 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Graduate Students 1959-1963, 3 folders (Box 34)
  - Graduate Students-Admission Cards 1965-1966 (Box 34)
  - Graduate Students-Admission, Special Cases 1967-1968 (Box 34)
  - Graduate Students-Assistants 1961-1964, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Graduate Students-Advisees 1948-1974, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Graduate Students-Fellows and Instructors 1959-1963, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Graduate Students-Form Letters 1963-1966, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Graduate Students-Jobs 1961-1962 (Box 34)
  - Graduate Students-Jobs 1963-1975, n.d., 5 folders (Box 35)
  - Graduate Students-Lists 1964-1967 (Box 35)
  - Graduate Students-Orientation Meetings 1962-1965 (Box 35)
  - Graduate Students-Prospective 1960-1963 Dec., n.d., 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Graduate Students-Prospective 1964-1966, n.d., 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Graduate Students-Qualification Data Sheets n.d. (Box 36)
  - Graduate Students-Teacher Placement Office n.d. (Box 36)
  - Hindi Reading Exam 1964-1966 (Box 36)
  - History Club 1952-1967, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - History Club Alumni Breakfast 1963-1965, n.d. (Box 36)
  - History Club-Alumni Newsletter 1952-1968 (Box 36)
  - History Club- Essays in History orders1962 (Box 36)
  - History Majors 1946-1964, n.d., & [1962-1964] (Box 36)
  - Honors Program 1962-1965 (Box 36)
  - Job Seeker Lists 1963-1965 (Box 37)
  - Jones, William, Papers of 1967-1970 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-General Correspondence 1963-1967, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-Carttar, Allan 1966 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-Crowe, Lawson 1966 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-Ford, Franklin 1966 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-Frantz, Joe 1969 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-Harbaugh, Janet 1968 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-Hughes, Thomas Parke 1966-1969 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-Nabrit, Samuel 1966-1969 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-Richard Lectures in Comparative History 1963 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-Riesman, David 1962 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-Wise, Max 1968 (Box 37)
  - Lecturers-miscellaneous 1963-1969, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Lee-duPont Letters 1971 (Box 37)
  - Manuscripts Collections 1959-1967 (Box 37)
  - Mary Washington College 1978 (Box 37)
  - Mason, George, Papers of 1962 (Box 37)
  - Monroe, James, Papers of 1967 (Box 37)
  - NASA History Project 1966 (Box 37)
  - N.D.E.A. Institute in American History 1965 Jan.-May (Box 37)
  - N.D.E.A. Institute in American History-Correspondence, etc. 1965-1966, n.d., 8 folders (Box 38)
  - N.D.E.A. Latin America Institute 1965 (Box 39)
  - News Stories-Clippings 1949-1964, n.d. (Box 39)
  - News Stories-Correspondence, Notes, and Photograph of Faculty 1962-1965, n.d. (Box 39)
  - News Stories-Press Releases 1959-1965, n.d. (Box 39)
  - Personnel 1965 (Box 39)
  - Personnel Committee 1972 (Box 39)
  - Phi Alpha Theta 1973 (Box 39)
  - Reading Lists for Incoming Students 1962, n.d. (Box 39)
  - State Department Internships 1965 (Box 39)
  - Stettinius Professorship 1966-1968 (Box 39)
  - Summer Institute for Asian Studies 1964-1965 (Box 39)
  - Summer Sessions 1961-1965, 4 folders (Box 39)
  - Virginia History Project 1970-1971 (Box 39)
- V. Papers re University of Virginia
  - Alumni Seminar 1960 (Box 40)
  - American Film Center 1960-1968 (Box 40)
  - Asian Studies-General File 1963-1965, n.d. (Box 40)
  - Asian Studies-Correspondence 1960-1967, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Asian Studies-South Asian Consortium 1968 (Box 40)
  - Center for Textual and Editorial Studies 1968 (Box 40)
  - Commencement 1966-1969, 4 folders (Box 40)
  - Commencement Parties 1967-1969 (Box 41)
  - Committee for Inter-cultural Education-Correspondence, Charter, Minutes, etc. 1960-1961, 3 folders (Box 41)
  - Committee for the Selection of Sesquicentennial Associates 1969, 2 folders (Box 41)
  - Committee on Educational Planning for George Mason College 1965-1967, 2 folders (Box 41)
  - Committee on Educational Policy 1969 (Box 41)
  - Committee on Personnel Policy and Special Activities 1963 (Box 41)
  - Committee on Registration 1962 (Box 41)
  - Committee on Teacher Evaluation 1962-1963 (Box 42)
  - Committee on University Cemetery 1974-1976 (Box 42)
  - Committee, Sesquicentennial 1967-1969 (Box 42)
  - Committee to Evaluate Curriculum of U.S. Naval Academy 1962-1967 (Box 42)
  - Committee to Select Art Department Chairman 1963 (Box 42)
  - Community College Teachers Fellowship Program-Correspondence 1968-1970 Apr. (Box 42)
  - Community College Teachers Fellowship Program 1970 May-1971, n.d. (Box 42)
  - Community College Teachers Fellowship Program-Descriptions, General Records, etc. 1969-1972, n.d., 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Community College Teachers Fellowship Program-Wellman Lecture 1967 (Box 42)
  - Community College Teachers Fellowship Program-Miscellaneous Notes, Printed Material n.d., 1966-1969, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Danforth Foundation-Correspondence, Proposals Miscellaneous 1962-1969, 4 folders (Box 43)
  - Endowed Chairs 1967 (Box 43)
  - Form Letters and Forms 1965-1969 (Box 43)
  - Furniture, Equipment, and Housing Space 1967-1968 (Box 43)
  - George Washington Papers 1967-1969 (Box 43)
  - Governor and Advisory Board 1969 (Box 43)
  - Graduate Awards Poster 1966-1970 (Box 43)
  - Graduate Dean Appointments 1962-1964, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Graduate Dean-Congratulations 1966-1969 (Box 44)
  - Graduate Faculty 1966-1969 (Box 44)
  - Graduate Incentive Fund 1966 (Box 44)
  - Hereford and Farmington Nov.-Dec. 1975 (Box 44)
  - Humanistic Sources Department 1969 (Box 44)
  - Inauguration of President Shannon 1969 (Box 44)
  - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences-Agendas, etc. 1948-1963, 3 folders (Box 44)
  - International Education Exchange Conference-Correspondence 1959-1960 (Box 44)
  - International Education Exchange Conference-Miscellaneous 1959-1960 (Box 45)
  - International Students 1957-1960 (Box 45)
  - International Students' Club 1958, n.d. (Box 45)
  - Kelly, Hugh P. 1965-1968 (Box 45)
  - Lecture Series-Correspondence, etc. 1962-1969, 3 folders (Box 45)
  - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 45)
  - Prospective Teacher Fellowship Program 1966 (Box 45)
  - Provost 1969 (Box 45)
  - Raven Society 1956-1965 (Box 45)
  - Recruiting and Enrollment 1965-1968 (Box 45)
  - Regional Conference on International Education Exchange 1959 (Box 46)
  - Report on President's Office 1959 (Box 46)
  - Report on University Graduate Study Program [1966] (Box 46)
  - Riopel, James L. 1967-1969 (Box 46)
  - Special Masters Degree Program-Correspondence, Proposals, etc. 1962-1969, 8 folders (Box 46)
  - Special Masters Degree Program-Questionnaires 1968, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - State Council of Higher Education 1966-1967 (Box 47)
  - Stettinius Papers Access Petitions 1969-1976 (Box 47)
  - Student Dissent 1967-1970 (Box 47)
  - Students, Special Cases 1961-1969 (Box 47)
  - Summer Session 1967-1971 (Box 47)
  - Summer Overseas Study 1964-1967 (Box 47)
  - Thomas Ball Scholarship 1964-1968 (Box 47)
  - Uruguayan Seminar 1960 (Box 47)
  - Winston Churchill Chair 1965 (Box 48)
  - Woodrow Wilson Fellowships-Correspondence, Lists, Notes, Printed Material 1962-1968, n.d., 3 folders (Box 48)
  - Work-Study 1966-1969 (Box 48)
- VI. Student Papers- Virginia History
  - Adams, Mary: "Albert Taylor Bledsoe" 1951 (Box 48)
  - Alexander, James: "The U.S. Banking System from the Civil War to 1912" 1974 (Box 48)
  - Alexander, James: "Prologue to Reform" 1974 (Box 48)
  - Anchors, Clanton: "The Primary Election of George C. Peery, 1933" 1963 (Box 48)
  - Barnard, William: "Pierson and the Folklore of Virginia Populism" n.d. (Box 48)
  - Bear, James: "Bibliography of Virginia History, 1865-1902" 1955 (Box 48)
  - Bell, Robert: "Ben Butler in Virginia" 1970 (Box 48)
  - Berton, William: "The Ku Klux Klan in the 1920's" n.d. (Box 48)
  - Bishop, John: "The Tale of Mutual Exploitation" 1976 (Box 48)
  - Blanton, S. Walker: "Virginia Politics, 1919-1922" n.d. (Box 48)
  - Boney, Francis: "Virginia's Civil War Governor" 1959 (Box 48)
  - Boney, Francis: "John Letcher and the Collapse of the Confederacy" 1960 (Box 49)
  - Breeden, James: The Tredegar Iron Works During the Civil War" 1959 (Box 49)
  - Brown, Robert: "The Rise and Fall of the Lynchburg Readjustors" 1966 (Box 49)
  - Bugg, James: "James M. Mason and the Compromise of 1850" n.d. (Box 49)
  - Buker, Margaret: "The Populist Revolt in Virginia" 1971 (Box 49)
  - Bull, Cornelius: "James Philemon Holcombe, Teacher and Patriot" 1956 (Box 49)
  - Butler, Leslie: "Prohibition and the Virginia Press" 1963 (Box 49)
  - Cahill, Audrey: Gilbert Carlton Walker" 1955 (Box 49)
  - Calhoun, Walter: "The African Warrior: W.E. Cameron, the Readjustor Candidate and the Virginia Gubernatorial Campaign of 1881" 1959 (Box 49)
  - Campbell, Otho: "John Sergeant Wise" 1974 (Box 49)
  - Carter, Henry: "Lewis H. Blair, Southern Prophet" 1959 (Box 49)
  - Chaunsly, Warren: "Frank G. Ruffin" 1957 (Box 49)
  - Clare, Carol: "The Woman Sufferage Movement in Virginia" 1968 (Box 49)
  - Clark, Margaret: "Facts Relating to the Surrender of Charlottesville, 1865" 1962 (Box 49)
  - Cole, Howson: "Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Readjuster" 1953 (Box 49)
  - Conlyn, Alexander: "Virginia During Redemption, 1867-1870" 1970 (Box 49)
  - Corley, Robert: "Conflicts in Black and White: Three Virginia Editors and the Brown Decision" 1975 (Box 49)
  - Council, Cameron: "John Powell: The Last Stand for Racial Integrity" 1965 (Box 49)
  - Cox, Harold: "Henry Clay Dean" 1953 (Box 49)
  - Cox, Harold: "The Jones Martin Campaign of 1911" 1954 (Box 49)
  - Crampton, Richard: "The Virginia Conservative Convention of 1877" 1959 (Box 49)
  - Crawley, William: "Tuck and the Election of 1945" 1967 (Box 49)
  - Crawley, William: "Tuck and the 1946 General Assembly" 1967 (Box 49)
  - Crawley, William: "Taxation During the Tuck Administration" 1969 (Box 49)
  - Crellin, Mark: "The Patrons of Husbandry in Virginia 1872-1880" 1972 (Box 49)
  - Crocker, John: "The Rocky Mount Fire, 1889" n.d. (Box 50)
  - Crutchfield, G.: "Governor Philip W. McKinney" 1959 (Box 50)
  - Culley, John: "State Efforts to Promote Immigration, 1865-1914" 1965 (Box 50)
  - Devine, Joseph: "Gubernatorial Campaign of 1925" 1963 (Box 50)
  - Dierenfield, Bruce: "The Rising Tide of Opposition to Rep. Smith, 1960-1965" 1976 (Box 50)
  - Donahue, Edward: "From Horse Cars to Busses in Charlottesville" n.d. (Box 50)
  - Edmunds, P. W.: "Notes on Harry F. Byrd and Carter Glass" n.d. (Box 50)
  - Ely, James: "The Campaign for Massive Resistance: Gubernatorial Election of 1957" 1968 (Box 50)
  - Farrell, Bruce: "The Civilian Conservation Corps...in Virginia" 1963 (Box 50)
  - Ferrell, Henry: "Claude Swanson and the Origins of the Byrd Organization" 1965 (Box 50)
  - Feldman, Melvin: "Anthony M. Kieley, Reconstruction Democrat" n.d. (Box 50)
  - Finger, Joel: "Fugitive Slaves in America, 1850-1859" n.d. (Box 50)
  - Flannagan, Allen: "The Effect of the Underwood Constitution on Education in Albemarle" n.d. (Box 50)
  - Fleshman, [?]: "John B. Minor" 1953 (Box 50)
  - Fleshman, [?]: "Woodrow Wilson and Carter Glass...in Currency Reform" n.d. (Box 50)
  - Frey, Neal: "Robert Lewis Dabney" 1970 (Box 50)
  - Fry, Andy: "The Redemption of the Fighting Ninth, the Congressional Election of 1922 in Virginia's Ninth District" 1971 (Box 50)
  - Fry, Joseph: "The Political Career of George Campbell Peery" 1970 (Box 50)
  - Fry, Joseph: "The Covington Sit-Down of 1937" 1974 (Box 50)
  - Fry, Joseph: "William Thomas Reed and Virginia Politics, 1925-1935" n.d. (Box 50)
  - Fry, Joseph & Tarter, Brent: "The Redemption of the Fighting Ninth and the Origins of the Byrd Organization" n.d. (Box 50)
  - Fuller, Melvin: "The Walton Act of 1894" 1956 (Box 50)
  - Gay, Thomas E.: "The Virginia State Corporation Commission" 1965 (Box 50)
  - Gipson, David: "The Early Career of Howard Kester" 1973 (Box 51)
  - Golden, Douglas: "The Richmond, Danville, and Piedmont Railroads, 1861-1866" n.d. (Box 51)
  - Gordon, Vesta: "John Sergeant Wise's The Lion's Skin as History" 1970 (Box 51)
  - Greer, Cecil: "Saltville and Salt Mining Operations During the Civil War" 1957 (Box 51)
  - Griffin, Jim: "The Last Ditch: James J. Kilpatrick's Doctrine of Interposition" 1975 (Box 51)
  - Gutterman, Laurel: "P.B. Young of the Norfolk Journal and Guide" 1966 (Box 51)
  - Hackle, Jean: "John R. Thompson and the Sectional Crisis, 1850-1873" 1951 (Box 51)
  - Hall, Al: "Virginia and the Roosevelt Purges of 1938" 1973 (Box 51)
  - Haluska, Jim: "The Reaction to Emancipation in Virginia" 1970 (Box 51)
  - Hawkes, Robert: "The Apprenticeship...of Harry Flood Byrd" 1967 (Box 51)
  - Hench, Atcheson: "The Phrase 'Solid South'" 1951 (Box 51)
  - Herndon, Melvin: "The Confederate States Naval Academy" 1955 (Box 51)
  - Hiatt, Rex: "Factionalism, Frustration, and Failure, 1870-1873" 1973 (Box 51)
  - Hickin, Patricia: "Henry Horatio Wells" 1963 (Box 51)
  - Hix, Thomas: "General John Daniel Imboden" n.d. (Box 51)
  - Holt, Wythe: "The Constitutional Convention of 1901-1902" 1967 (Box 51)
  - [Holt, Wythe]: "Virginia Political History Since 1965: A Bibliography" n.d. (Box 51)
  - Hopewell, John: "John Garland Pollard" n.d. (Box 51)
  - Holt, Wythe: "Industrial Growth in Virginia, 1900-1920" 1968 (Box 52)
  - Holt, Wythe: "The Economic and Cultural Development of Virginia" 1968 (Box 52)
  - Holt, Wythe: "Political Connections and Beliefs of the Democrats" 1975 (Box 52)
  - Holt, Wythe: "The Struggle Between Woodrow Wilson and Senator Martin" n.d. (Box 52)
  - Honaker, Lowell: "The Darkest Day in Virginia's History" 1959 (Box 52)
  - Horwatt, Sally: "The Evolution of William Henry Ruffner's Views of the Negro" 1965 (Box 52)
  - Hutcheson, Drewry: "Republicans and Populists in Virginia Politics" n.d. (Box 52)
  - Jennings, James: "The Readjusters and the Gubernatorial Election of 1881" n.d. (Box 52)
  - Johnson, K.: "Presidential Election, 1912" 1956 (Box 52)
  - Jones, Archer: "Readjusters in the House of Representatives" 1951 (Box 52)
  - Judkins, Shirleen: "The Massenburg Bill" 1975 (Box 52)
  - Kirby, Jack: "The Campaign of 1917" 1963 (Box 52)
  - Kirby, Jack: "The Democratic Organization and its Challenges, 1899-1922" 1965, n.d. (Box 52)
  - Kirby, Jack: "Westmoreland Davis" 1966 (Box 52)
  - Lancaster, Edwin: "Captain S.L. Thompkins" 1959 (Box 52)
  - Lank, Roy: "Horn Dissertation" 1969 (Box 52)
  - Larsen, William: "Factional Rivalries in Virginia Politics" 1960 (Box 52)
  - Laushey, David: "Election of Colgate Darden as Governor of Virginia, 1941" 1963 (Box 52)
  - Leary, W.: "A Case Study of Negro Business Enterprise 1881-1910" n.d. (Box 52)
  - Lee, Alan: "Judge Alexander Rives" 1959 (Box 52)
  - Leebrick, Gloria: "Virginia Farmers' Alliance and Industrial Union, 1887-1897" 1973 (Box 52)
  - Lewis, John: "The Election in 1896" 1959 (Box 52)
  - Link, William: "The Virginia Farmers' Alliance, 1887-1892" 1977 (Box 53)
  - Lowe, Richard: "The Republican Party in Virginia" 1966 (Box 53)
  - Maddex, J. Pendleton: "Bourbon Redemption in Virginia, 1866-1879" n.d. (Box 53)
  - Martin, Lewis: "Murder on the Lawn-the Shooting of Mr. Davis" 1973 (Box 53)
  - Martin, Lewis: "The Faculty of the University of Virginia, 1830-1840" 1974 (Box 53)
  - [Militano, Mary D. ?]: "Frank G. Ruffin" n.d. (Box 53)
  - Miller, Frank: "Richard H. Edmonds, Industrial Exponent of the South" 1959 (Box 53)
  - Montague, Robert: "Andrew Jackson Montague" 1956 (Box 53)
  - Moon, Norman: "Allen Granberry Thurman" 1959 (Box 53)
  - Moore, James: "The Readjuster Elite" 1968 (Box 53)
  - Moore, James: "The University and the Readjusters" n.d. (Box 53)
  - Moore, John: "James Gaven Field, Populist" n.d. (Box 53)
  - Nelms, Richard: "John William Mallet: Confederate Chemist" 1959 (Box 53)
  - Noel, Edgar: "The Election of 1873" 1959 (Box 53)
  - Nolan, John: "James Hay and the 1912 Army Appropriation Bill" 1965 (Box 53)
  - Norman, Robert: "Drive for an Anti-Lynching Law in Virginia, 1919-28" 1974 (Box 53)
  - Ours, Robert: "Virginia's Funding Act of 1871" 1965 (Box 53)
  - Park, John: "Republicans and Reconstruction" 1976 (Box 53)
  - Park, John: "The Virginia Constitutional Convention" 1979 (Box 53)
  - Paschal, Donald: "Frank Stringfellow and Confederate Intelligence" n.d. (Box 53)
  - Payne, Phillip: "Robert Whitehead" 1975 (Box 54)
  - Pendleton, Eldridge: "World War I and Virginia's Negroes" 1970 (Box 54)
  - Pendleton, Eldridge: "The Position of the Negro in Wartime, 1916-1919" n.d. (Box 54)
  - Peterson, Richard: "Views of the Entry of the United States into World War I" 1972 (Box 54)
  - Phillips, James: "The 1928 Election in Virginia: The Silent Issue" 1975 (Box 54)
  - Pickford, Herbert: "The Hampton Roads Peace Conference" 1955 (Box 54)
  - Poindexter, Harry: "Aftermath of the Bryan Campaign" 1954 (Box 54)
  - Poindexter, Harry: "Henry Clay Marchant and ...the Charlottesville Woolen Mills" 1955 (Box 54)
  - Poss, Judith: "The Virginia Gubernatorial Campaign of 1909" 1963 (Box 54)
  - Poston, Charles: "The Rise of Henry Carter Stuart, 1855-1913" 1969 (Box 54)
  - Poston, Charles: "Henry Carter Stuart" n.d. (Box 54)
  - Prillaman, Jerry: "General John Daniel Imboden" 1959 (Box 54)
  - Protos, George: "A Study of the Constitution of 1870" 1975 (Box 54)
  - Pulley, Raymond: "The May Movement of 1899" 1965 (Box 54)
  - Pyron, Darden: "Virginia Newspaper Project" n.d. (Box 54)
  - Ray, William: "Public Opinion and Thomas S. Martin" 1965 (Box 54)
  - Readnour, Harry: "The Cavalcade Campaign" n.d. (Box 54)
  - Readnour, Harry: "A Study of a Transitional Phase in Virginia Politics, 1896-1897" 1963 (Box 54)
  - Reck, Henry: "Prospectus for a Study of the Lynchburg Foundry Company" n.d. (Box 54)
  - Rhinesmith, W.: "Gubernatorial Campaign of 1949 in Virginia" 1963 (Box 54)